<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>KenCochrane.net</title><link href="http://kencochrane.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://kencochrane.net/feeds/djangomaine.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://kencochrane.net/</id><updated>2013-02-19T08:24:24-05:00</updated><entry><title>Intro to Python and Django Presentation</title><link href="http://kencochrane.net/blog/2013/02/intro-to-python-and-django-presentation/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-19T08:24:24-05:00</updated><author><name>Ken Cochrane</name></author><id>tag:kencochrane.net,2013-02-19:blog/2013/02/intro-to-python-and-django-presentation/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a talk at a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.DjangoMaine.com"&gt;DjangoMaine&lt;/a&gt; meetup introducing folks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;. There wasn't enough time to go over everything, so I tried to pick and choose the parts that I felt where important to go over, in order to have a good overview of what Python and Django is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this was useful to the folks that attended. If so, it would be really helpful to know what parts you would like to know more about. Then we can have some follow up talks doing a deeper dive into those select topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="future-tutorials"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if there is a demand, I'm willing to do a half or whole day Python and Django tutorial, where we would be able to take the time needed to go into all the different topics, so that you would have a good understanding of each one, when you left. Ideally I would probably break up the sessions into beginner, intermediate, and advanced so that people can move to the different levels as they get more familiar and comfortable with Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to offer a talk to local high schools. If we have enough kids that are interested, I'd be willing to go to your high school and give a talk and introduce these topics to the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more about Django, please let me know. I don't want to waste my time doing all the work preparing for a tutorial, if there isn't enough demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="slides"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn't record the talk, but you can find my slides below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="width: 710px;height: 612px;" id="slides_container"&gt; &lt;script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="21c679705ccf0130a3061231381a97d7" data-ratio="1.2994923857868" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="download"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides are also available to download in pdf form: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerd.s3.amazonaws.com/presentations/21c679705ccf0130a3061231381a97d7/intro-to-python-django_v2.pdf"&gt;Intro to Python and Django Presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, or comments, feel free to contact me via the comments below, or on Twitter (&amp;#64;KenCochrane)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="djangomaine"></category></entry></feed>