<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>KenCochrane.net</title><link href="http://kencochrane.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://kencochrane.net/feeds/tag_recruiters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://kencochrane.net/</id><updated>2013-02-06T20:17:48-05:00</updated><entry><title>Dear Recruiters</title><link href="http://kencochrane.net/blog/2013/02/dear-recruiters/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-06T20:17:48-05:00</updated><author><name>Ken Cochrane</name></author><id>tag:kencochrane.net,2013-02-06:blog/2013/02/dear-recruiters/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Recruiters,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are probably reading this because I sent you a link in response to a recent job you contacted me about. Since most of you know nothing about me (even though most of this information is on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/kencochrane"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; page). I'm going to tell you a little bit about myself, and after reading this if you feel the job that you are trying to fill, is a good match for me, then feel free to respond. If you are going to respond, please make sure you follow the criteria I listed at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Me:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently work for a great company called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dotcloud.com"&gt;dotCloud&lt;/a&gt;, which is based in San Francisco, and I'm happy. So it would take a really good offer to even make me think about wanting to leave. What is a really good offer you might ask? I list my current minimum offer towards the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the company that I work for is based in San Francisco, I do not live there, I live in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portland,_Maine"&gt;Southern Maine&lt;/a&gt;. So, unless this job of yours allows remote workers, don't even bother. Also, unless you plan on covering the cost of selling my house, don't even mention relocation assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;: Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server OS&lt;/strong&gt;: Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop OS&lt;/strong&gt;: OSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases&lt;/strong&gt;: MySQL, PostgreSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Stores&lt;/strong&gt;: Redis, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version control&lt;/strong&gt;: git, mercurial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Server&lt;/strong&gt;: nginx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javascript library&lt;/strong&gt;: jQuery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are deal breakers for me. If I have to work with the following technologies. Don't even bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Windows (any flavor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="minimum-offer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minimum offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I don't make this today, but like I said before, it would need to be a really good offer before I would consider leaving my current job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salary&lt;/strong&gt;: $200,000+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vacation&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 weeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signing bonus&lt;/strong&gt;: $25,000+ including Stock options&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company&lt;/strong&gt;: Needs to be technology company doing cool and exciting things. I prefer smaller companies, and don't want to work for a big company that has lots of office politics that get in the way of getting things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="offer-criteria"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Offer Criteria:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have read all of the above, and you still feel you have a job that is right for me, then please send me the following information. &lt;strong&gt;Failure to do so, will result in your message getting deleted with no reply.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name of the company and their location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The salary. (Don't say, it depends on experience, look at my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/kencochrane"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; profile, figure out how much experience I have and then tell me the salary you are offering.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A description of the job you would like me to apply for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of the current technologies related to the job in question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I read your message and I find it interesting, I will be in contact. If you don't hear from me, assume I'm not interested and please don't keep badgering me. It isn't very becoming of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Cochrane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="recruiters"></category></entry></feed>